# **ERDOO KUHWA**

Full Stack Developer

### Contact



Houston TX



832.462.4469



erdoo.kuhwa@gmail.com



https://github.com/erdookuhwa



https://erdookuhwa.netlifv.app

# Skills

ReactJS / Redux / React Native

**NodeJS** 

HTML

CSS / Sass

Debugging

**ExpressJS** 

# Certifications

Google IT Automation with Python

Certified Associate in Project Management (CAPM)

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals

## **Affiliations**

National Society of Black Engineers

Women Techmakers

Society of Women Engineers (SWE)

Institute of Electrical/Electronics Engineers (IEEE)

Project Management Institute (PMI)

My interest led me to be a self-taught Software Developer for the past 2+ years and now recent bootcamp graduate. Employing knowledge from my arsenal of skills has led me to build and develop full stack and React apps using JS, HTML, designed with CSS, Sass.

## **Experience**

2018 - 2021

### **Application Support Engineer**

DNV GL

- Performed analyses on software application and functionality suggesting improvements
- Troubleshot interface software and debugged application codes to improve functionality performance by 30%
- Established the root causes of application errors and escalated serious concerns
- Updated records using scripts saving time by 90%
- Consulted with the software development team, internal users, and clients to improve application performance
- Reviewed application requirements and interface design to ensure compatibility with existing applications

2017 - 2018

#### **Data Analyst**

Industrial Information Resources

- Designed and maintained data systems and databases using SQL and
- Fixed coding errors and other data related problems
- Produced high quality visualization reports for executive leaders which improved their decision making time by 50%

2013 - 2015

## **Enterprise Systems Engineer**

Layer3 Ltd

- Managed domain and all subdomain registration and hosting
- Managed and deployed website content using CMS
- Designed, developed and deployed Cloud systems using VMware
- Liaised with project manager to determine project scope and project timeline which were rigorously adhered to without overspill 99% of the time
- Oversaw and monitored Servers, PCs, printers and all applications running on them including but not limited to CRM, SIP Server and all phone extensions, Port Forwarder, File Servers etc.

#### Education

April 2021

Full Stack Immersive Software Engineering

Byte Academy (Bootcamp)

December 2017 3.80

Master of Science: Industrial/Engineering Management

University of Houston - Clear Lake

April 2013 3.97

Bachelor of Engineering: Electrical and Electronics Engineering

University of Agriculture